Vikas Reddy Kunduru

vikas-kunduru.github.io - kunduruvikasreddy@gmail.com - +61 412 276 153

Career Objective

A GIS professional with 4.3 years of experience in both Local Government and private sectors, looking forward to associating myself with an organization wherewith there is an opportunity to learn, contribute and upgrade my creative skills for the development of the organization and myself.

Professional Employment History

Murrindindi Shire Council - Technical Officer Assets

July 2020 - Till Date

- Developed scripts for data monitoring and creation of new Public register for integration.
- Design and produce CRM Work Order monitoring system in Power Bl.
- Developed practical solution for Accessibility/Mobility program based on spatial analysis.
- Simplify data handover process by integrating multiple asset categories in one spot.
- Monitoring integration errors between Python Assetic and Intramaps.
- Updating existing Council asset registers (Assetic) with new or amended data.
- Adding new assets to GIS layers in Council's adopted mapping system QGIS.

Brimbank City Council - GIS Analyst (WIL)

Dec 2019 - May 2020

- Increased data accuracy by managing GIS databases for efficient data-sharing practices.
- Contributed mapping and GIS research assistance to Asset & Property Services using Deep learning & FME automation processes.
- Worked closely with GIS, Urban Design, and Assets departments to enhance data management procedures and meet business goals.
- Assisted GIS team with quality analysis of automated feature extraction.

Brimbank City Council - Graduate GIS Analyst

Nov 2018 - April 2019

- Performed a suitability analysis to identify bike tracks, recreation centers, and skate parks in Golden plains shire council.
- Developed a naming custodian to maintain data integrity while migrating data to SQL Server 2016.
- Provided research and logistical support to developed a geo-database for Urban design using GIS tool.
- Managed to analyze a sample region to estimate the pervious and impervious land cover change over 10 year of time.

Brimbank City Council - Student GIS Volunteer

Jan 2018 – Oct 2018

- Created a geo-database for building services department resulting in more efficient inspection of permits and penalties in regards to outdoor swimming pools/Spas.
- Updated Bicycle network and logged the dataset into information system.
- Mapped road intersections by automating vector direction for Golden plain shire council.
- Assisted internal clients with spatial data requests & electronic data management using TRIM.

Grace Detailed GIS Services, Melbourne - Student GIS Analyst

April 2018 - April 2018

- Georeferenced Melbourne's old imagery using Arcmap tools.
- Conducted data capturing and quality analysis.
- Willow mapping for Melbourne water pervious impervious for black town city council.
- Built spatial databases for Melbourne Water, Black town city council (NSW).

Education

Education Centre of Australia - ACS professional year **La Trobe University** - Master of Information and Communication Technology May 2019 – May 2020 Feb 2017 – Dec 2018

Skills

GIS Software: Esri's Arcmap, MapInfo Pro, Quantum GIS (QGIS).

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL.

Asset Management software: Confirm Enterprise.

Data analysis / ETL Processing tools: FME. Business intelligence tool: Power BI.

Enterprise software: Exponare Enquiry, SSA, TRIM, Authority. **Development:** Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bulma, ReactJS.

Projects

Deep Learning

- Classified aerial imagery using ENVI.
- Analyzed and extracted tree canopy coverage in sample area using remotely sensed image analysis.
- Tools used: ENVI, Mapinfo, FME.

Aerial Analysis

- Analyzed pervious and impervious land cover for a selected region.
- Compared extracted data from 2009 & 2018 to draw the development rate overtime.
- Tools used: Nearmaps, QGIS.

Tree Plantation Potential

- Collected potential sites for tree plantation for Urban design team.
- Automated the tree size category based on urban design operating principles.
- Tools used: MapInfo, Confirm, FME.

Know Your Bin Day (In progress)

- Building a web/mobile based application to show user of their bin collection day.
- Built wireframes and prototype showing how this helps user with notifications from council or user's custom reminders.
- Tools used: QGIS, SQLite, Bulma.

Referees

Mr. Jian Zhao (jzhao@murrindindi.vic.gov.au)

- Asset Engineer, Murrindindi Shire Council Tel: +61 3 5772 0333

Mr. Caleb Kantepudi (calebk@brimbank.vic.gov.au)

- Asset and Spatial Information Officer (GIS), Brimbank City Council Tel: +61 3 9249 4227

Dr. JoshpharKunapo (joshphar.kunapo@gracegis.com.au)

- Director, Grace Detailed-GIS Services, Victoria Mob: +61 431 562 226